ROB FARIS

robfarisvideography@gmail.com Additional portfolio examples available on request robfaris.github.io/portfolio

I am a Motion Graphics Designer and Graphics Artist working in Washington, DC. I have over 15 years of experience animating and designing for both the public and private sector.

EXPERIENCE

Duty First Consulting, Senior Consultant (Video and Design Specialist)

Vienna, VA - April 2018 to Present

- Lead and manage the Graphics Team
- Create custom 508-compliant animated and multimedia videos for government clients
- Design a variety of digital and print graphics, documents, and social media toolkits
- Create, design, and test HTML5 web-based trainings, and other content integrated into online LMS platforms

National Capitol Contracting, LLC.

October 2015 to April 2018

Audio-Visual Production Specialist at US Dept. of HHS

Washington, DC - January 2017 to April 2018

- Responsible for HHS live video streams and digital signage design
- Operated camera, switching, and audio equipment in HHS Television Studio
- Organized and operated audio/video for government conferences and events

Event Technology Specialist

Arlington, VA – April 2016 to January 2017

- Edited and created integrated motion graphic overlays for all video productions
- Managed, led, and coordinated all of NCC's Live Event contracts
- Operated live audio and video equipment for a variety of high-profile government conferences, webcasts, webinars, etc.

Editing and Production Associate

Arlington, VA – October 2015 to April 2016

- Edited video, and created closed and open captions for government and private sector clients
- Operated cameras during live webcast events

Public Information Office at the Town of Vienna, Production Associate

Vienna, VA – March 2015 to August 2015

- Filmed and edited original television content and advertisements for TVCN
- Operated robotic cameras and switcher simultaneously during live television broadcasts
- Responsible for the Town's event photography and multimedia design

Monroe Langston, Inc., Video Producer and Editor

Savannah, GA — May 2013 to September 2013

- Developed and edited tutorial videos about computer software
- Designed and created graphics, flyers, and logos

VOLUNTEER AND FREELANCE WORK

iCan Shine, Inc. Cofradía's Bilingual School Innovideo Productions, LLC Arlington, VA Cofradia, Honduras Washington, DC

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Skilled in Motion Graphics creation and 2D and 3D Graphic Design (Photoshop, After Effects, Illustrator, InDesign, Maya, Blender, Nuke, etc)
- Skilled video editor and sound designer (Adobe Premiere, Avid, FinalCut, Adobe Audition, ProTools, Audacity)
- Adept in web design (HTML/CSS/Javascript), Wordpress, and Google Apps/Analytics
- Experienced with web training concepts (SCORM 1.3, LMS integration) using Adobe Captivate
- Live Audiovisual Events and AV Technology (Live switching, Live sound, Webcasting, WebEx)
- Experienced videographer using video, broadcast, DSLR, and film cameras

EDUCATION

Savannah College of Art and Design

M.F.A. Film and Television

Savannah, GA — 2011 to 2014

Allegheny College

B.A. Communication Arts Concentration: Film Production Meadville, PA - 2007 to 2011